

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in customer service ensuring that customers are always fully satisfied with the product and service they receive. Possessing strong analytical problem solving skills and adaptiveness, having worked alongside teams to efficiently create and develop mobile-first applications with a pronounced user experience.

EDUCATION

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

FULL STACK CODING BOOTCAMP Grad. July 2020 | Evanston, IL

LINKS

Portfolio:// alexbailon.net Github:// alex-bailon LinkedIn:// alex-bailon

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Node.js • Express • Javascript jQuery • HTML5 • CSS3 • Bootstrap 4 Cypress • MySQL • MongoDB • Vue.js React.js • Vuex • Redux • Vuetify Python • C# • Handlebars.js • Docker

DEVELOPMENT

Mobile-First & Responsive Design • Test Driven Development • Object Oriented Programming • Fundamentals of Web Development • Data Structure Algorithms • Database Organization Information Security • State Management

EXPERIENCE

FUSION92 | JUNIOR DEVELOPER (CONTRACT)

Oct 2020 - Present | Chicago, IL

- Provide Back-end and Front-end support to clients and projects.
- Created full stack apps using Node.js/Express for the back end, Nuxt.js/Vuejs for server side rendering, and Docker/Cypress.io for effortlessly deployment and testing.
- Work with development team to deliver on clients expectations.

TRILOGY EDUCATION | Instructional Staff(Web Dev Boot Camp)

Oct 2020 - Present | Evanston, IL

- Work with students in a class and one on one setting to ensure students success throughout the full stack boot camp.
- Topics cover in the course include HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, and more.

LIFESTREAM BLOOD BANK | HOSPITAL SERVICES TECH II

Nov 2018 - Oct 2020 | Freelance | Rosemead, CA

• Received, processed and transported blood products. Imported blood products, returns and transfers of inventory.

FUSION92 | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (FREELANCE)

May 2020 - Aug 2020 | Chicago, IL

- Created and developed marketing material using MJML.
- Use **Email on Acid** to test and ensure generated **HTML** is fully responsive on all operation systems and email clients.
- Worked with teams of 5-10 along with other departments to ensure projects met and exceeded clients expectations.

BANK OF THE WEST | Service Banker

Dec 2017 - Nov 2018 | Alhambra, CA

• Processed customer transactions (deposit check/cash, make payments, wire transfers) and serviced customer accounts.

PROJECTS

FETCH | LIVE: FETCH-WOOF-312.HEROKUAPP.COM

July 2020 | Chicago, IL

Full-stack application that allows users to match their pets with other pets so that they may set up playdates and allow their pets to be more socially active. Used React.js, Redux, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bcrypt.js, Passport.js and Express.

HOME BODY | LIVE: HEALTH-APP-2020.HEROKUAPP.COM/

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 | Chicago, IL

Full-stack health application that helps users keep track of daily calorie, fat, sugar, and carb intake with information organized in charts. Used MySQL, Sequelize, Handelbars.js, Bcrypt.js, Passport.js, Chart.js and Express.

FLYTE | LIVE: KYLERES.GITHUB.IO/FINANCE_APP/

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 | Chicago, IL

Front-end finance application that lets users view stock prices and news related to that stock. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Chart.js and Materialize.